Anderson, Arvid Files 6192
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Arvid Anderson Files
1968-2005
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Anderson, Arvid
6192
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Records.
5837328
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Ashley Myers, May 30, 2005
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 24, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Arbitration, Industrial; Collective bargaining; Anderson, Arvid A. (Arvid Asa), 1930-; Georgia Power Company; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers. Local 84; AFSCME. Council 48 (Milwaukee, Wis.); Milwaukee (Wis.). Police Department; American Federation of Government Employees. Local 506; United States. Department of Justice. Federal Bureau of Employes; United States Postal Service; American Postal Workers Union; American Federation of Government Employees. Local 919; United States. Bureau of Prisons; United States Penitentiary in Leavenworth, Kansas; Weyerhaeuser Company; Paper, Allied-Industrial, Chemical and Energy Workers International Union; L3 Communications/Electrodynamics Company; Monona Lake (Wis.). Fire fighters; National Post Office Mail Handlers; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers. Local 134
5837328
- I. Speeches and addresses, 1968-1976, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Public Employees and Collective Bargaining: Comparative State and Local Experience., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Comparison of State, Federal, and Local Laws in the Field of Public Employment., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Scope of Bargaining in Public Employment., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Public Collective Bargaining and Social Change., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Labor Relations In Public Employment., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Compulsory Arbitration Under State Statutes., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Making Collective Bargaining Work in Public Employment: Changing of the Establishment., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Public Employee Collective Bargaining: The Changing of the Establishment., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Experience in Municipal and State Sectors: Some Lessons and Guidelines., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Public Sector Bargaining: National Issues, Needs, and Prospects., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- School Policy and Collective Bargaining., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lessons from Interest Arbitration in the Public Sector: The Experience of Four Jurisdictions., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bargaining Issues in the Public Sector: More in 74., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Statement of Arvid Anderson, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Ohio Legislative Service Commission Conference for Legislators on Public Employee Labor Relations: Impasse Resolution Procedures., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Public Employee Collective Bargaining: Money, Unions, and the Law., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- The Public Sector: The Labor Management Crisis and Conflict Resolutions in our Cities- New York City., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Remarks by Arvid Anderson., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- What the Federal Government Can Learn From the State and Local Experience- A Neutrals View., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Democracy in Trade Unions., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Money, Unions, Politics, and the Public Interest., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Implications of National League of Cities v. Usery., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Public Sector Bargaining and the New York City Fiscal Crisis., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Issues in the 80s: The Changing Role of Neutrals., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- The Role of the Arbitrator in a Depressed Economy., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- New and Changing Demands on the Neutral: The Impact on the Parties and the Process., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- The Metro North Strike- A Mediators View., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Lets Make Final Offer Final., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Final Offer Arbitration., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Public Sector Collective Bargaining in the 1980s: The Unfinished Agenda., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Federal Sector Collective Bargaining in 1984: The Unfinished Agenda. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Public Sector Collective Bargaining in 1984: The Unfinished Agenda. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- American Arbitration Association Interest Arbitration Seminar., 1984 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Remarks of Arvid Anderson., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- The Ohio Bargaining Impasse Procedure: An Outsiders View., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- The Role of Law in Arbitration., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- The Prospects for Public Sector Labor Law- Two Central Issues., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Public Sector Collective Bargaining Lessons From Recent Experience., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Public Sector Dispute Resolution Lessons From Recent Experience., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Mediation Immunity: Some Reasons Why., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Achieving Acceptability for Government Conciliation Agencies., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Statement of Arvid Anderson., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- The Role of Arbitration in Resolving Labor Disputes in the United States., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Public Sector Collective Bargaining Twenty Years Later: The Unfinished Agenda., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- An Arbitrators View of Drug and Alcohol Testing in the Workplace., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Presenting An Interest Arbitration Case: An Arbitrators View., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Twenty Years of Living Under the Taylor Act., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Interest Arbitration: The Alternative to the Strike., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Impasse Procedures: Whats Available and What Works Best?, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- An Arbitrators View of Drug and Alcohol Testing in the Workplace., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- II. Arbitration files, 1994-2005 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Arbitration between Georgia Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 84, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  Scope and Contents
  Arbitration award
- Arbitration between Milwaukee District Council 48, AFSCME, AFL-CIO, and City of Milwaukee (Police Department)., 1998 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Arbitration between American Federation of Government Employees Local 506 and United States Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Employees, FCC Coleman, 1998-2004 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Working contracts., 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Complex Contingency Plan signature sheets., 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Correspondence., 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Unions motion to bifurcate hearing., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Agencys response to the Unions request to a bifurcated hearing., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Proceedings, Volume I., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Proceedings, Volume II., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Proceedings, Volume III., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Proceedings, Volume IV., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Agencys closing argument., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Agencys reply brief., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Unions post-hearing brief regarding procedural arbitrability., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Appendix to Unions post-hearing brief regarding the merits (folder 1)., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Arbitration between Georgia Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 84., 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Arbitration award., 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Arbitration between Milwaukee District Council 48, AFSCME, AFL-CIO, and City of Milwaukee (Police Department)., 1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Arbitration award., 1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Arbitration between American Federation of Government Employees Local 506 and United States Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Employees, FCC Coleman., 1998-2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Working contracts., 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Complex Contingency Plan signature sheets., 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence., 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Unions motion to bifurcate hearing., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Agencys response to the Unions request to a bifurcated hearing., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Proceedings, Volume I., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Proceedings, Volume II., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Proceedings, Volume III., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Proceedings, Volume IV., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Agencys closing argument., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Agencys reply brief., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Unions post-hearing brief regarding procedural arbitrability., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Appendix to Unions post-hearing brief regarding the merits (folder 1)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Appendix to Unions post-hearing brief regarding the merits (folder 2)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Union post-hearing brief., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Appendix to Unions post-hearing brief regarding procedural arbitrability (folder 1)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Appendix to Union's post-hearing brief regarding procedural arbitrability (folder 2)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Unions exceptions to arbitration award (folder 1)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Unions exceptions to arbitration award (folder 2)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Agency submitted issue statement. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  n.d
- Additional materials (folder 1). (Box 2, Folder 26)
  n.d.
- Additional materials (folder 2). (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Additional materials (folder 3). (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Arbitration between United States Postal Service and American Postal Workers Union, AFL-CIO., 2000 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Award summary., 2000 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Arbitration between American Federation of Government Employees, Local 919, and Federal Bureau of Prisons, United States Penitentiary Leavenworth, Kansas., 2003 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Arbitrators decision and award., 2003 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Arbitration between Palm Beach County CTA, Matthew Tomasula grievant, and the School Board of Palm Beach County., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Award summary., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Arbitration between Georgia Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Local 84., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Transcript., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Brief on behalf of International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 84., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Award summary., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Additional material. (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Arbitration between Weyerhaeuser and Paper, Allied Industrial, Chemical and Energy Workers International Union, Local 0319., 2004- 2005 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Transcript (folder 1)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Transcript (folder 2)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Brief of the Union., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Award summary., 2005 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Additional materials. (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Exhibits. (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Arbitration between International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 134, and L3 Communications / Electrodynamics Company., 2004- 2005 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Preliminary statement., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Brief on behalf of Union and aggrieved employee., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Original transcript (folder 1)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Original transcript (folder 2)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Award summary., 2005 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Additional materials. (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Arbitration between City of Milwaukee, and District Council 48, AFSCME, AFL-CIO., 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Transcript of proceedings (folder 1)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Transcript of proceedings (folder 2)., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Brief of Milwaukee District Council 48 and Local 33., 2005 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Brief of behalf of the City of Milwaukee, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Award summary., 2005 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Additional material. (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Arbitration between City of Monona, and Firefighters Local 311., 2004 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Exhibits (folder 1). (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Exhibits (folder 2). (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Exhibits (folder 3). (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Exhibits (folder 4). (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Exhibits (folder 5). (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Arbitration between United States Postal Service, and National Postal Mail Handlers Union, Local 318., 2005 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Award summary., 2005 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Additional material (folder 1). (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Additional material (folder 2). (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Opening statement., 2005 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Award summary., 2005 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Additional material (folder 1) (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Additional material (folder 2) (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Additional material (folder 3) (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Additional material (folder 4) (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Additional material (folder 5) (Box 3, Folder 13)
- III. Articles and interviews, 1974, 1976, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Association of Labor Mediation Agencies Resolution: Federal Legislation for Public Employees, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  July, 1974
- What the Federal Government Can Learn From the State and Local Experience- A Neutrals View, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Friedman, Clara H., Oral History: Labor Arbitrators, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  17-Jul-84
- IV. Instructional material, 2000-2004 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Annual Refresher Training, 2000-2004 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Wisconsin Employment Relations Commission: Arbitration between Cornell School District and Teacher, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Cornell, Wisconsin. Not University.
- Arbitrations, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Arbitrations, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Arbitrations folder 1, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Arbitrations folder 2, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Arbitrations, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Arbitrations, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Arbitrations, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Arbitrations, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Arbitrations, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Arbitrations, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Arbitrations, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Arbitrations folder 1, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Arbitrations folder 2, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Arbitrations, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Arbitrations, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Arbitrations, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Arbitrations, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Arbitrations, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Arbitrations folder 1, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Arbitrations folder 2, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Arbitrations, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Arbitrations, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Arbitrations, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Arbitrations, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- 1968 Sanitation Strike, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Impact of Public Sector Bargaining, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- An Interest Arbitration Demonstration, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Miscellaneous, 1980-1996 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Arbitrations, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Arbitrations folder 1, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Arbitrations folder 2, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Arbitrations folder 3, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Arbitrations folder 4, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Arbitrations folder 1, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Arbitrations folder 2, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Arbitrations folder 1, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Arbitrations folder 2, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Arbitrations folder 3, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Arbitrations folder 4, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Arbitrations folder 1, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Arbitrations folder 2, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Arbitrations folder 3, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Arbitrations folder 1, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Arbitrations folder 3, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Arbitrations, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Arbitrations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Chapter II (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Scrapbook
- Girl Scout Badges. Linda Anderson (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Baseball Arbitrations (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Speech Material. Arvid Anderson (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Lindsay Goldberg (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Strikes (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Local 1226, Rhinelander City Employees, AFSCME (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Misc. Booklets and Magazines (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Misc. folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Misc. folder 2 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Wisconsin Employment Relations Commission (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Arbitration with Maple Creek Mining Inc. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Arbitration With Hamilton Standard (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Arbitration With United States Postal Service (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Arbitration With Pratt Whitney (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Arbitration With Lee County (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Arvid Anderson (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Arbitration With Verizon (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Arbitration With Bell Atlantic New Jersey (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Arbitration With International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 827 AFL-CIO (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Arbitration With State of Florida (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Arbitration With Okeelanta Corp. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Arbitration With City of Wausau (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Arbitration With United Paperworkers International Union (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Arbitration With International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Arbitration With the City of Ocala (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Arbitration With Kimberly-Clark Corp. (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Arbitration With Charlotte County School Board (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Arbitration With Ladish Co., Inc. (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Arbitration With Copaz Packing Corp. (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Arbitration With Pace International (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Arbitration With Police and Firefighters Associations (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Arbitration With Sikorsky Aircraft (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Arbitration With the City of Callaway, Florida (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Arbitration With Dept. of the Air Force (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Arbitration With City of Boston (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Arbitration With the Village of Winnetka (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Arbitration/ Impasse With University of Central Florida (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Arbitration With New York Telephone Co. (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Misc. Arbitrations (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Reports (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Reports (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 32)